<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>watches on Simon Bromander's training blog</title><link>https://simonstrives.com/tags/watches/</link><description>Recent content in watches on Simon Bromander's training blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simonstrives.com/tags/watches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I'm abandoning the Apple Watch Ultra and going back to Garmin Forerunner 955</title><link>https://simonstrives.com/p/why-im-abandoning-the-apple-watch-ultra-and-going-back-to-garmin-forerunner-955/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simonstrives.com/p/why-im-abandoning-the-apple-watch-ultra-and-going-back-to-garmin-forerunner-955/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://simonstrives.com/p/why-im-abandoning-the-apple-watch-ultra-and-going-back-to-garmin-forerunner-955/images/watches.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Why I'm abandoning the Apple Watch Ultra and going back to Garmin Forerunner 955" />&lt;p>When Apple released the Apple Watch Ultra I was stoked, as a owner of prev Garmin Fenix 5 and the Forerunner 955 I wanted to try something new. I&amp;rsquo;m also heavily invested in the Apple ecosystem, so having one less system to worry about felt nice. I was quite happy with my 955, except for the Garmin Connect app which felt clunky and old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started out with my new Ultra and Workoutdoors app for recording workouts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pros:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Great customisations abilities for Workoutdoors&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Built in workout app works quite well, good integration with the action button, even if it can only mark laps and pause/resume at this point&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Amazing screen&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Cons:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I miss the physical buttons, the action button just wont cut it&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Trouble to load in pre-defined/structured workouts&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Pairing a HRM strap is cumbersome&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Can not wear the watch over a jacket (hey its cold in Sweden during winter) without disabling wrist detection(and hence losing a lot of features)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These takeaways made me rethink my watch usage and I&amp;rsquo;m now back with Garmin 955 as my main training watch. I&amp;rsquo;m still debating with myself if I should keep the Ultra as an everyday watch. What I love about the ultra for everyday use:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Apple Home integration, turn on/off things within reach all the time&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sonos app Lyd for controlling speakers at hand all the time&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The Remote app for controlling Apple TVs&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Timer app is outstanding and easy to use&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Sleep tracking is great, accurate and easy to understand&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Auto unlocking my phone + macbook is a smooth feature to have&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>So, to wrap this up: After trying the Apple Watch Ultra, I returned to their Forerunner 955 I’m still considering the Apple Watch Ultra for everyday use due to its great customisation abilities, built in workout app, amazing screen, and integration with Apple Home, Sonos, Remote, and Timer apps.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>