<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>stroller on Simon Bromander's training blog</title><link>https://simonstrives.com/tags/stroller/</link><description>Recent content in stroller on Simon Bromander's training blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simonstrives.com/tags/stroller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First impressions; Thule Chariot Sport 2</title><link>https://simonstrives.com/p/first-impressions-thule-chariot-sport-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simonstrives.com/p/first-impressions-thule-chariot-sport-2/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://simonstrives.com/p/first-impressions-thule-chariot-sport-2/images/thule-chariot-sport2.png" alt="Featured image of post First impressions; Thule Chariot Sport 2" />&lt;p>At first, I began jogging with the kids in a regular stroller, but this was only a temporary solution and I eventually decided to purchase a proper running stroller. Due to having twins, I had to switch my plans of getting a Thule Glide and instead opted for the Thule Chariot. This model has adjustable suspension and disc brakes and comes with multiple accessories, like the Bike, Run and Ski options. As the kids are still young, I also purchased the Thule Infant Sling to secure them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first impressions of the Chariot are that it is easy to maneuver when set up in running mode. The infant sling is great for our little ones (weighing 3.5kg and 5kg). Although it is not advised to run with a stroller until the babies can support their own head, I think running easy on flat roads being careful is not worse than walking with the stroller on a gravel path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This stroller will be beneficial to my training regime, as it will help relieve my wife of some of her duties and also give me a good workout. It is a great way to get out and explore new areas, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the freedom and flexibility that it will provide.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>