<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Running on Simon Bromander's training blog</title><link>https://simonstrives.com/categories/running/</link><description>Recent content in Running on Simon Bromander's training blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://simonstrives.com/categories/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>First impressions; Thule Chariot Sport 2</title><link>https://simonstrives.com/p/first-impressions-thule-chariot-sport-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simonstrives.com/p/first-impressions-thule-chariot-sport-2/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://simonstrives.com/p/first-impressions-thule-chariot-sport-2/images/thule-chariot-sport2.png" alt="Featured image of post First impressions; Thule Chariot Sport 2" />&lt;p>At first, I began jogging with the kids in a regular stroller, but this was only a temporary solution and I eventually decided to purchase a proper running stroller. Due to having twins, I had to switch my plans of getting a Thule Glide and instead opted for the Thule Chariot. This model has adjustable suspension and disc brakes and comes with multiple accessories, like the Bike, Run and Ski options. As the kids are still young, I also purchased the Thule Infant Sling to secure them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first impressions of the Chariot are that it is easy to maneuver when set up in running mode. The infant sling is great for our little ones (weighing 3.5kg and 5kg). Although it is not advised to run with a stroller until the babies can support their own head, I think running easy on flat roads being careful is not worse than walking with the stroller on a gravel path.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This stroller will be beneficial to my training regime, as it will help relieve my wife of some of her duties and also give me a good workout. It is a great way to get out and explore new areas, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the freedom and flexibility that it will provide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How getting kids changed my approach to training and planning</title><link>https://simonstrives.com/p/how-getting-kids-changed-my-approach-to-training-and-planning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://simonstrives.com/p/how-getting-kids-changed-my-approach-to-training-and-planning/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://simonstrives.com/p/how-getting-kids-changed-my-approach-to-training-and-planning/images/stroller-jog.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post How getting kids changed my approach to training and planning" />&lt;p>It’s fair to say that my training volume dropped quite significantly since we got kids. A while back I felt anxious about it, but I’ve gotten in to acceptance and now embracing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From having almost unlimited time to train maxing out 15hours week to being able to train only when there’s a small free slot to do so…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This new situation led me to rethinking my training plan, instead having a training manifesto. The days of structured predictable training are over, at least for now. They will come back at some point, but now having a plan will cause me to stress more about getting sessions done than actually enjoying training.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, this is my new approach to semi structured training.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Main goal: IM70.3&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Biggest weakness: Brick runs/running on tired legs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Longest time spent: Bike&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>With these prerequisites in mind, I wanted to focus on building my bike fitness and run. As going to a pool regularly will take too much time as a new parent i choose to just swim when I got the opportunity and it’s also the shortest time spent activity so I’d thought it’s better to build bike fitness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My bike sessions are focused on building endurance and power, with a mix of intervals and long rides. I try to get in at least one long ride each week, and a few shorter rides on the other days. I also make sure to include some strength training on the bike, like hill climbs and sprints, to help with my overall power.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My goal for 2023 is to complete Ironman 70.3 in Jönköping. As of today I have not defined any expected finish times, but I&amp;rsquo;ll do that during the summer once my training routine settles and I&amp;rsquo;ll progress my training.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll post my updated training manifesto soon.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>